<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="6" moduleid="259" modulename="journal" contextid="468">
  <journal id="6">
    <name>Set a personal teaching goal for creating a student-centered learning environment</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span size="3"&gt;Set a goal for incorporating strategies for student-centered learning (SCL) into your teaching practice. If you currently address and incorporate SCL strategies into your teaching, write a goal that either increases your focus on SCL in your lesson planning and design, or that refines your teaching practices to more effectively give students power to control the structure and content of their learning. The purpose of setting a goal is to help you have an end in mind, i.e., a way to refine your practice of teaching.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span size="3"&gt;&lt;span face="Calibri"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Setting and achieving goals for &lt;em&gt;your own&lt;/em&gt; professional development can help you ensure positive change in your teaching practice and support your commitment to be an  effective teacher of adult learners. Remember that your goal statements need to be specific and realistic (attainable and within a specified time period). It also is important that your goals be measurable so that you will be able to identify whether or not you have met your goal. A framework for ensuring that your goals meet the above-mentioned criteria is the ABCD framework. View the following resource to help &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; set specific and measurable goal statements: &lt;a title="Reading: Steps to Refine your Goals Statements" href="$@PAGEVIEWBYID*261@$" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span class="nolink"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Steps to Refine your Goals Statements&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; resource&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Click Start or Edit my journal entry to submit or update your reflection. Be sure that the audience for your goal is you (not your students) because this is a goal for your own professional growth as a teacher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span size="3"&gt;Remember that your goal statements need to be specific enough to ensure change in teaching practice. View the following resource to help you set specific and measurable goal statements: &lt;span&gt;&lt;a title="Reading: Steps to Refine your Goals Statements" href="$@PAGEVIEWBYID*261@$" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span class="nolink"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Steps to Refine your Goals Statements&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; resource&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <days>0</days>
    <grade>-4</grade>
    <timemodified>1523910384</timemodified>
    <entries>
    </entries>
  </journal>
</activity>