<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="40" moduleid="238" modulename="page" contextid="447">
  <page id="40">
    <name>Helping Students Increase their Writing Fluency: Giving Students Voice through Bio-Poems and Collaborative Paragraphs (Video)</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;" size="3"&gt;Research informs us that, to help students become less intimidated by and more comfortable with writing, we need to increase the amount of writing they do. Some strategies used to build writing fluency represent examples of student-centered learning principles in that they engage learners in collaborative activities and allow them choice in topics to write about, effectively giving them voice in the selection of materials and strategies.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;"&gt;Research informs us that, to help students become less intimidated by and more comfortable with writing, we need to increase the amount of writing they do. Some strategies used to build writing fluency represent examples of student-centered learning principles in that they engage learners in collaborative activities and allow them choice in topics to write about, effectively giving them voice in the selection of materials and strategies. Watch this Video on &lt;em&gt;Increasing Students’ Writing Fluency&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;embed height="480" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" src="https://www.youtube.com/v/G7wPgV8WpTI?version=3&amp;amp;hl=en_US&amp;amp;rel=0" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;[&lt;span style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;&lt;a title="PDF - opens in new window - Transcript for Student Fluency" href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Online%20SCL%20Course_Helping%20Your%20Students%20tocrease%20their%20Writing%20Fluency_Rev%20%281%29.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #0000ff;"&gt;Transcript of presentation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;[The video content presented here requires JavaScript to be enabled and the latest version of the Adobe Flash Player. If you do not have the latest version, please update Adobe Flash Player by downloading it here: &lt;a href="https://get.adobe.com/flashplayer/" title="Adobe Flash Player" target="_blank"&gt;https://get.adobe.com/flashplayer/&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>2</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:1:{s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>23</revision>
    <timemodified>1523909209</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>