<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="99" moduleid="558" modulename="page" contextid="867">
  <page id="99">
    <name>Student Centered Learning: Preparation for College and Careers [Math] (Video)</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;Please watch this video to learn about student centered learning in relation to preparation for college and careers.&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <content>&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;" size="3"&gt;Adult students come to class with learning needs concerning personal interests, family and community life, furthering education and training, and the workplace.  The challenge for instructors is to address all of these areas of need, providing a strong foundation for students to operate independently in any of these domains. Today, there are many frameworks, standards, and guidelines detailing what students need to know and be able to do to be prepared for and successful meeting 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; century demands. These sets of skills provide extensive direction on content that teachers should cover and outcomes students should achieve. Along with the other instructional practices within the TEAL Toolkit, student centered teaching will foster deeper learning and increase learner autonomy so students can make educational gains and reach desired performance outcomes.  The following presentation provides examples of some of the current thinking on college- and career- readiness and how to incorporate a student centered learning approach to help students prepare for and succeed in the future.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium;" size="3"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;object width="640" height="480"&gt;&lt;param name="movie" value="//www.youtube.com/v/XSD_zCZQf34?hl=en_US&amp;amp;version=3&amp;amp;rel=0" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowFullScreen" value="true" /&gt;&lt;param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /&gt;&lt;embed src="https://www.youtube.com/v/XSD_zCZQf34?hl=en_US&amp;amp;version=3&amp;amp;rel=0" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="640" height="480" allowscriptaccess="always" allowfullscreen="true" /&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style="text-align: center;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p align="center"&gt;[&lt;a title="PDF - opens in new window - Transcript Math Student Centered Learning" href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/TEAL_Course%208_Student%20Centered%20Learning-9-18-13.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Transcript of Presentation&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium;" size="3"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;" size="3"&gt;Lesson Design Principles for Math&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span size="3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="@@PLUGINFILE@@/map_cc_teacher_guide.pdf" title="pdf - opens in new window" target="_blank"&gt;Classroom Challenges - Formative Assessment Lessons: A Brief Guide for Teachers and Administrators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: small;" size="3"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mathematics Assessment Project: Assessing 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; Century Math&lt;/i&gt; is a collaboration by the Shell Center for Mathematical Education at the University of Nottingham, and the University of California at Berkeley to produce assessments and tools to assist in the implementation of the Common Core State Standards. A key instructional feature promoted in the Mathematics Assessment project is the Classroom Challenge. There are two primary Classroom Challenge lesson types:  (1) concept development lessons in which the teacher uncovers students’ prior knowledge and moves to developing understanding of concepts and mathematical connections; and (2) problem solving lessons which begin with assessments and end with student application of mathematical knowledge to complex and real world problem solving tasks. The resource below describes when and how to use the Classroom Challenges in math and includes steps for encouraging “productive struggle” with the concepts, collaborative problem solving, deeper learning, and increased student responsibility in the learning process. In particular, the lesson design principles outlined on pages 11-12 support student centered learning.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;" align="center"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;" align="center"&gt;&lt;br /&gt; [&lt;span style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;The video content presented here requires JavaScript to be enabled and the latest version of the Adobe Flash Player. If you do not have the latest version, please update Adobe Flash Player by downloading it here: &lt;a href="https://get.adobe.com/flashplayer/" title="Adobe Flash Player" target="_blank"&gt;https://get.adobe.com/flashplayer/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium;" size="3"&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium;" size="3"&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium;" size="3"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span lang="EN" style="font-size: x-small;"&gt;Above are some links to information provided by other organizations. These links are provided for the user's convenience. The U.S. Department of Education cannot guarantee the accuracy of the information at these sites. The inclusion of these links is not intended to reflect their importance; nor is it intended to endorse any views or products of these organizations. For further information, see our &lt;a href="http://www2.ed.gov/about/contacts/gen/othersites/edrespol.html" target="_blank"&gt;Collection Scope and Criteria for Inclusion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium;" size="3"&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium;" size="3"&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
    <contentformat>1</contentformat>
    <legacyfiles>0</legacyfiles>
    <legacyfileslast>$@NULL@$</legacyfileslast>
    <display>5</display>
    <displayoptions>a:1:{s:10:"printintro";s:1:"0";}</displayoptions>
    <revision>17</revision>
    <timemodified>1523909322</timemodified>
  </page>
</activity>