<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section id="61">
  <number>0</number>
  <name>$@NULL@$</name>
  <summary>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Welcome to the online course, &lt;span&gt;&lt;em&gt;Student-Centered Learning, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;for adult education teachers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Student-centered learning&lt;/b&gt; (&lt;abbr title="Student-centered learning"&gt;SCL&lt;/abbr&gt;) is an instructional approach that focuses on the needs of students and allows students to influence the content, activities, materials, and pace of learning according to their interests and needs. Although it often is necessary for teachers to provide information to students through lecture and demonstration, sometimes teachers can over-emphasize the role of transmitter of information and not place enough attention on students’ specific learning needs. In student-centered instruction, the student is placed at the center of the teaching-learning dynamic, so that transmission of information is secondary to student's needs, abilities, interests, and learning preferences. In this way, the teacher in a student-centered classroom becomes a facilitator of learning rather than simply a transmitter of knowledge. Student-centered learning acknowledges student voice as central to the learning experience for every learner. This approach not only promotes active student involvement, but the student-teacher dialogue that is characteristic of &lt;abbr title="Student-centered learning"&gt;SCL&lt;/abbr&gt; also can be a renewing experience for teacher learning. Research confirms the positive influences of &lt;abbr title="Student-centered learning"&gt;SCL&lt;/abbr&gt; instructional approaches: properly implemented &lt;abbr title="Student-centered learning"&gt;SCL&lt;/abbr&gt; can lead to increased student motivation to learn, greater retention of knowledge, deeper understanding, and increased persistence in educational programs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;</summary>
  <summaryformat>1</summaryformat>
  <sequence>223,3246,1052,1053,1054</sequence>
  <visible>1</visible>
  <availablefrom>0</availablefrom>
  <availableuntil>0</availableuntil>
  <showavailability>0</showavailability>
  <groupingid>0</groupingid>
</section>